Benjamin Stanfield

www.linkedin.com/in/benjaminstanfield

4520 36th Ave SW, Apt.25 (314) 498-4795

Seattle, Washington 98126 towheadcreative@gmail.com

Experienced Graphic Designer and Independent Developer with over a decade of knowledge in design and web development with demonstrated customer interfacing skills and creative problem solving in multiple disciplines. PHP knowledge allowed for seamless transition of prepress variable data processing during recent transitions of work at Creative Communications.

Areas of Expertise

 $HTML \cdot Linux \cdot PHP \cdot SQL \ Database \cdot CSS \cdot Javascript \cdot C++ \cdot Python \cdot HTML5 \cdot Wordpress \cdot Drupal \cdot Marketo \cdot Mailchimp \cdot Adobe \ Creative \ Cloud \cdot Quark$

Work Experience

University of Washington Creative Communications – Seattle, Washington October 2020 - Current

Production Coordinator

Generate all quote requests from Account Managers.

Process all incoming orders and transfer to the necessary production workstream.

Daily huddles with supervisory staff, sales, and other production teams.

Research and develop new revenue streams by working with management and production staff.

Manage order intake for Seattle Children's Hospital; including customer communication and file prepress work.

Verify all quotes for final billing.

All file prepress including variable data merging and XMPie functionality for data formatting including QR codes, table structure, and data manipulation.

University of Washington Creative Communications – Seattle, Washington May 2019 - October 2020

Bindery Technician I

Complete all incoming orders from all production streams promptly.

Operate and maintain all machinery managed by the bindery.

Daily huddles with supervisory staff, sales, and other production teams.

Research and implement new tools and production processes to increase efficiency as well as create new revenue streams.

Prompt responses to all bindery questions from other departments.

Lantern Press LLC - Seattle, Washington

Oct. 2017 - May 2019

Print Room Lead

Manage all toner-based and latex-based printing.

Handle template impositions for all products.

Restructure printing processes to more efficiently print and stage products for manufacture.

Delegate printing responsibilities within the print production team to maximize production.

Rolled out processes to produce a new die-cut sticker product line.

Manage e-commerce retail printing and packaging from printer to shipping.

Manage inventory of all raw materials for all products printed in the print room.

Daily communication with sales, operations, and packaging departments to ensure smooth production.

Track weekly e-commerce sales and communicate wins and opportunities to team.

Jaffe Book Solutions - Hazelwood, Missouri

Feb. 2016 - Sep. 2017

Pre-Press Specialist

Verify file integrity through pre-flight checks with Pitstop Pro.

Make any file modifications, based on a soft-proof process, using Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator or InDesign.

Develop and lead implementation of new workflow processes for Print-on-Demand service (including software research and development, manpower, as well as production needs and costs).

Impose files and double-check layouts to send to the printers.

Customer quote generation.

Regular communication with customers to relay product turnaround time and quality expectations.

Manage paper and toner inventory as well as created and tracked equipment service calls.

Point of contact for bindery facility in absence of the Production Manager.

Lead trainer for all bindery equipment and print production.

Liaison between bindery staff and customers.

Guided tours of plant facilities.

Champion of the Great Game of Business ideals.

Jaffe Book Solutions - Hazelwood, Missouri

Jan. 2014 - Feb. 2016

Bindery Production

Work with production equipment: laminator, creaser, electric cutters, hardcover binding equipment, perfect binder.

Regular communication with management to ensure a high quality and efficient turnaround time.

Track daily totals of bindery employees to measure success.

Manage lamination inventory and place inventory orders as needed.

Create and track equipment service calls.

Relayed daily progress reports for production contracts to the ownership team.

Lead trainer for production equipment and procedures.

Kirkwood Public Library - Kirkwood, Missouri

Jun. 2013 - Feb. 2015

Teen Librarian / IT Technician

Created, promoted, and coordinated community events focused on teen engagement.

Created point-of-sale and web graphics for teen events as well as other promotional projects.

Maintain teen room collection.

Monitor all patrons in the teen area.

Perform IT work throughout the library including: troubleshooting computers and answering patron questions.

Worked with Director of Technology to concept and design new library website including: Prototyping wireframe, research, feature list, cost breakdown, asset design, work with contractors for various plugin development, integration of library services, roll-out and upkeep.

Develop and teach technology classes for library patrons.

Education

Certificate in Front-End Development With Html, CSS & Javascript - University of Washington - Professional and Continuing Education - Seattle, Washington (November 2022)

Completed Bachelor of Fine Art in Graphic Design - Webster University- Webster Groves, Missouri (2008)

Completed Associates of Art - East Central College - Union, Missouri (2005)